Stacy London

Front-End Developer at Atlassian

Summary

Senior Front-End Engineer with over 16 years of web development experience.

- Experienced in architecting, designing, and coding cross-browser high-traffic customer-facing websites and web applications.
- Modern UI developer who emphasizes incorporating user feedback, usability/UX, responsive design, progressive enhancement, and mobile first approaches to design & coding.
- International work experience (United Kingdom, Netherlands, Hong Kong).
- Resourceful and passionate about the possibilities of the web platform.

I'm currently focused on single page web applications and my specialties include: HTML5, CSS3 (LESS), JavaScript (ES2015), Ajax, JSON, jQuery, Backbone.js, Ember.js, Ember Data, Underscore/Lodash, Jasmine, Sinon, jQuery Mobile, Handlebars, RequireJS, Grunt (Node.js, NPM), responsive design, cross-browser compatibility, and mobile first approaches.

I believe JavaScript unit testing is important and that adding quality controls to workflows (e.g. JSHint, JSCS (now ESLint), CSSLint, HTML and CSS validators) helps teams learn/grow as well as helps to ensure that websites/apps work well across a myriad of browser, platforms, and devices.

I enjoy teaching/mentoring others, selecting technology stacks, setting direction for best practices, digging into new tech, and exploring ways to make web development more productive and enjoyable.

I love learning and keeping up on the constantly evolving set of web technologies. I also really value craftsmanship and getting to know something really well.

Experience

Front-End Developer at Atlassian

December 2016 - Present

Working on the Bitbucket Cloud team.

Lead Front-End Engineer at ShoreTel

August 2016 - November 2016 (3 months)

Senior Technical Lead Software Engineer

Manager, User Interface Engineering at ShoreTel

January 2016 - August 2016 (7 months)

ShoreTel acquired Corvisa and the end of December 2015 and the deal was finalized on January 7th, 2016.

Manager, Software Engineering

Lead Front-End Engineer at Corvisa

June 2015 - January 2016 (7 months)

Staff Software Engineer

Senior Application Architect (Front-End Development) at Northwestern Mutual

August 2012 - June 2015 (2 years 10 months)

- * Defined the strategy for building websites / web applications.
- * Defined the web technology stack that web developers can use to create new websites / web applications.
- * Defined best practices and guidance for the web development community.
- * Led front-end engineering & architecture on the main corporate website re-platform and re-design project. Created a mobile first, responsive designed site.
- * Led front-end engineering & architecture on Internet-facing customer web application.
- * Led front-end engineering & architecture on two hybrid mobile web applications using PhoneGap that extended CRM capabilities.

Application Architect (Front-End Development) at Northwestern Mutual

October 2010 - August 2012 (1 year 10 months)

Led front-end engineering & architecture on Internet-facing customer web application.

Systems Consultant (Web Application Development) at Northwestern Mutual

May 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 5 months)

I developed financial web applications & web services for the Investment Products & Services (Annuities) area. Web technology stack included Struts on JEE (Java, JSP, JSTL), HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Ajax, JSON). Web Services technology stack included JAX-WS and XML. All running in WebSphere on Unix. IDE used was IBM's Rational Software Architect (Eclipse variant).

Senior Programmer Analyst (E-Commerce) at Kohl's Department Stores

October 2006 - May 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Working with Java, JSP, the Blue Martini commerce platform, and Endeca (search) I developed components & provided rotational 24x7 support for http://www.kohls.com.

Milwaukee Representative

2005 - 2007 (2 years)

I was the Milwaukee Representative for Filter Magazine. It was a volunteer position where I promoted musicians/band and upcoming shows across the city by hanging posters/flyers as well as promoting at live shows. http://filtermagazine.com

IT Systems Analyst (Web Application Development) at Sealed Air Diversey Care

May 2000 - October 2006 (6 years 5 months)

Used ASP.NET/C# with Microsoft Content Management Server, Microsoft Commerce Server (and Microsoft Solutions for Internet Business) to develop global (multi-lingual) content management websites (intranet, internet, and extranet). Managed the code & content deployment process across environments as well as supported the server environment with MS Operations Manager. Designed & implemented a web application to help customers in the UK streamline the management of fleets of cleaning machines. This included creating functional & technical specifications, use cases, UML diagrams, and database diagrams. I managed an offshore development team and integrated & deployed code across environments. I developed & deployed order processing functions of an online store for JD Denmark and Switzerland.

Education

University of Oxford

Recommended for Credit, Modern Art History, 2003 - 2003

Activities and Societies: The Survival Of Painting from 1968-2002

Marquette University

Letters of Completion, Java/JSP, 2002 - 2002

University of Wisconsin-Whitewater

BBA, MIS (Web Technologies), 1997 - 2001

Activities and Societies: Member of the Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi, member of Phi Beta Lambda (Business Group - Future Business Leaders of America), start-up member of Students for Internet Responsibility and Freedom, Diversity Advocate speaker, membership in the Who's Who Among Students in American Colleges and Universities, member of the Golden Key National Honor Society, invited to be published in the The National Dean's List, member of OSRA (Organizational Systems Research Association)

Stacy London

Front-End Developer at Atlassian



Contact Stacy on LinkedIn